Guide to the Wilfred Thomason Grenfell Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1855-1958, undated; Series XIV; 11.50 linear feet (28 boxes)
  W. T. Grenfell Family contains pictures of W. T. Grenfell's wife and of their children. For each individual the photographs are arranged chronologically and are followed, in the cases of A. E. M. Grenfell and W. T. Grenfell, Jr., by narrative sequences. These are followed by a chronologically arranged group of pictures containing two or more family members, and photographs of residences outside of Newfoundland and of pets.
  A. S. Grenfell Family contains photographs of W. T. Grenfell's parents and brothers, as well as of their residences. They are arranged chronologically within each folder.
  Hutchinson Family contains chronologically arranged photographs of W. T. Grenfell's mother's family.
  arranged alphabetically by location.
  Miscellaneous contains photographs not classified in any of the above categories.
  Albums contains, in chronological order, the albums which could not be dismantled. They are in fragile condition and should be used only after the photocopies have been consulted.
  - Mission Stations
    - Batteau, Labrador
      - General views (Box 41, Folder 1)
        Photograph No. 1-7
      - Harbor (Box 41, Folder 2)
        Photograph No. 8-11
      - "Liv'eres" (Box 41, Folder 3)
        Photograph No. 12
      - Mission services and facilities (Box 41, Folder 4)
        Photograph No. 13-14
    - Battle Harbor, Labrador
      - General views (Box 41, Folder 5-6)
        Photograph No. 15-89
      - Agriculture and livestock (Box 41, Folder 7)
        Photograph No. 90
      - Cemetery (Box 41, Folder 8)
        Photograph No. 91-94
      - Church (Box 41, Folder 9)
        Photograph No. 95-96
      - Harbor (Box 41, Folder 10)
        Photograph No. 97-132
      - Hunting and fishing (Box 41, Folder 11)
        Photograph No. 133-145
      - "Liv'eres" (Box 41, Folder 12)
        Photograph No. 146-176
      - Hospital (Box 41, Folder 13)
        Photograph No. 177-218
      - Mission services and facilities (Box 41, Folder 14)
        Photograph No. 219-229
      - Mission staff (Box 41, Folder 15)
        Photograph No. 230-261
      - School (Box 41, Folder 16)
        Photograph No. 262-263
    - Cartwright, Labrador
      - General views (Box 41, Folder 17)
        Photograph No. 264-291
      - Agriculture and livestock (Box 41, Folder 18)
        Photograph No. 292-294
      - Cemetery (Box 41, Folder 19)
        Photograph No. 295-297
      - Government buildings (Box 41, Folder 20)
        Photograph No. 298-299
      - Harbor (Box 41, Folder 21)
        Photograph No. 300-304
      - Hospital (Box 41, Folder 22)
        Photograph No. 305-317
      - Hudson Bay Company (Box 41, Folder 23)
        Photograph No. 318
      - Hunting and fishing (Box 41, Folder 24)
        Photograph No. 319
      - "Liv'eres" (Box 41, Folder 25)
        Photograph No. 320-342
      - Mission services and facilities (Box 41, Folder 26)
        Photograph No. 343-377
      - Mission staff (Box 42, Folder 27)
        Photograph No. 378-383
      - Orphanage (Box 42, Folder 28)
        Photograph No. 384-403
      - School (Box 42, Folder 29)
        Photograph No. 404-416
    - Englee, Newfoundland (Box 42, Folder 30)
      Photograph No. 417-421
    - Flower's Cove, Newfoundland (Box 42, Folder 31)
      Photograph No. 422-432
    - Forteau, Labrador
      - General views (Box 42, Folder 32)
        Photograph No. 433-443
      - Agriculture and livestock (Box 42, Folder 33)
        Photograph No. 444-467
      - Church (Box 42, Folder 34)
        Photograph No. 468
      - Harbor (Box 42, Folder 35)
        Photograph No. 469-479
      - Lighthouse (Box 42, Folder 36)
        Photograph No. 480-485
      - "Liv'eres" (Box 42, Folder 37)
        Photograph No. 486-492
      - Mission services and facilities (Box 42, Folder 38)
        Photograph No. 493-510
      - Mission staff (Box 42, Folder 39)
        Photograph No. 511
    - Harrington, Quebec (Box 42, Folder 40)
      Photograph No. 512-540
    - Indian Harbor, Labrador
      - General views (Box 42, Folder 41)
        Photograph No. 541-564
      - Harbor (Box 42, Folder 42)
        Photograph No. 565-570
      - Hospital (Box 42, Folder 43)
        Photograph No. 571-577
      - "Liv'eres" (Box 42, Folder 44)
        Photograph No. 578-580
      - Mission staff (Box 42, Folder 45)
        Photograph No. 581-586
    - Muddy Bay, Labrador (Box 42, Folder 46)
      Photograph No. 587-604
    - Mutton Bay, Quebec (Box 42, Folder 47)
      Photograph No. 605-612
    - North West River, Labrador
      - General views (Box 42, Folder 48)
        Photograph No. 613-622
      - Agriculture and livestock (Box 42, Folder 49)
        Photograph No. 623-624
      - Church (Box 42, Folder 50)
        Photograph No. 625
      - Harbor (Box 42, Folder 51)
        Photograph No. 626-628
      - Hospital (Box 42, Folder 52)
        Photograph No. 629-635
      - "Liv'eres" (Box 42, Folder 53)
        Photograph No. 636-640
      - Mission services and facilities (Box 42, Folder 54)
        Photograph No. 641-645
      - Mission staff (Box 42, Folder 55)
        Photograph No. 646-647
    - Pilley's Island, Newfoundland (Box 42, Folder 56)
      Photograph No. 648-650
    - Red Bay, Labrador (Box 42, Folder 57)
      Photograph No. 651-664
    - Roddickton, Newfoundland (Box 42, Folder 58)
      Photograph No. 665-690
    - St. Anthony, Newfoundland
      - General views (Box 43, Folder 59-61)
        Photograph No. 691-878
      - Agriculture and livestock (Box 43, Folder 62)
        Photograph No. 879-946
      - Cemetery (Box 43, Folder 63)
        Photograph No. 947-949
      - Church and parsonage (Box 43, Folder 64)
        Photograph No. 950-956
      - Community activities and special events (Box 43, Folder 65-66)
        Photograph No. 957-1102
      - Government buildings (Box 43, Folder 67)
        Photograph No. 1103-1105
      - Wilfred T. Grenfell's house (Box 43, Folder 68)
        Photograph No. 1106-1168
      - Harbor (Box 44, Folder 69-71)
        Photograph No. 1169-1382
      - Hospital (Box 44, Folder 72-74)
        Photograph No. 1383-1539
      - Hunting and fishing (Box 44, Folder 75)
        Photograph No. 1540-1560
      - Industry (Box 44, Folder 76)
        Photograph No. 1561-1577
      - Lighthouse (Box 44, Folder 77)
        Photograph No. 1578-1580
      - "Liv'eres" (Box 44, Folder 78)
        Photograph No. 1581-1642
      - "Liv'eres" (Box 45, Folder 79-80)
        Photograph No. 1643-1750
      - Mission services and facilities (Box 45, Folder 81-82)
        Photograph No. 1751-1851
      - Mission staff (Box 45, Folder 83-84)
        Photograph No. 1852-2004
      - Orphanage (Box 45, Folder 85)
        Photograph No. 2005-2058
      - School (Box 45, Folder 86)
        Photograph No. 2059-2080
    - St. Mary's River, Labrador
      - General views (Box 45, Folder 87)
        Photograph No. 2081-2099
      - Agriculture and livestock (Box 46, Folder 88)
        Photograph No. 2100-2108
      - Hospital (Box 46, Folder 89)
        Photograph No. 2109-2126
      - Hunting and fishing (Box 46, Folder 90)
        Photograph No. 2127-2130
      - "Liv'eres" (Box 46, Folder 91)
        Photograph No. 2131-2133
      - Mission services and facilities (Box 46, Folder 92)
        Photograph No. 2134-2140
      - Mission staff (Box 46, Folder 93)
        Photograph No. 2141-2147
    - Square Island, Labrador (Box 46, Folder 94)
      Photograph No. 2148-2155
    - White Bay, Newfoundland (Box 46, Folder 95)
      Photograph No. 2156-2159
  - Moravian Stations
    - Hebron, Labrador (Box 46, Folder 96)
      Photograph No. 2160-2166
    - Hopedale, Labrador (Box 46, Folder 97)
      Photograph No. 2167-2187
    - Makkovik, Labrador (Box 46, Folder 98)
      Photograph No. 2188-2193
    - Nain, Labrador (Box 46, Folder 99)
      Photograph No. 2194-2222
    - Ramah, Labrador (Box 46, Folder 100)
      Photograph No. 2223-2224
    - Unidentified (Box 46, Folder 101)
      Photograph No. 2225-2234
  - Other Newfoundland and Labrador Sites
    - Adlavik Island, Labrador (Box 46, Folder 102)
      Photograph No. 2235
    - Anatalak Bay, Labrador (Box 46, Folder 103)
      Photograph No. 2236-2239
    - Back Bay, [Labrador?] (Box 46, Folder 104)
      Photograph No. 2240-2241
    - Bar Island, [Newfoundland?] (Box 46, Folder 105)
      Photograph No. 2242
    - Barred Harbor, Newfoundland (Box 46, Folder 106)
      Photograph No. 2243-2244
    - Bay Bulls, Newfoundland (Box 46, Folder 107)
      Photograph No. 2224
    - Bear Cove, [Labrador?] (Box 46, Folder 108)
      Photograph No. 2246
    - Bear's Gut, [Labrador?] (Box 46, Folder 109)
      Photograph No. 2247
    - Belle Isle, Newfoundland (Box 46, Folder 110)
      Photograph No. 2248-2260
    - Black Duck Cove, [Labrador?] (Box 46, Folder 111)
      Photograph No. 2261-2262
    - Blanc Sablon, Quebec (Box 46, Folder 112)
      Photograph No. 2263-2270
    - Blue Lake, Newfoundland (Box 46, Folder 113)
      Photograph No. 2271-2280
    - Blue Stone Island, Labrador (Box 46, Folder 114)
      Photograph No. 2281-2284
    - Bonne Esperance, Quebec (Box 46, Folder 115)
      Photograph No. 2285-2289
    - Boulter's Rock, [Newfoundland?] (Box 46, Folder 116)
      Photograph No. 2290-2292
    - Brehat, Quebec (Box 46, Folder 117)
      Photograph No. 2293
    - Brigus, Newfoundland (Box 46, Folder 118)
      Photograph No. 2294
    - Brown's Cove, [Labrador?] (Box 46, Folder 119)
      Photograph No. 2295
    - Canada Bay, Newfoundland (Box 46, Folder 120)
      Photograph No. 2296-2302
    - Cape Charles, Labrador (Box 46, Folder 121)
      Photograph No. 2303-2315
    - Cape Harrison, Labrador (Box 46, Folder 122)
      Photograph No. 2316
    - Cape Lupton, Labrador (Box 46, Folder 123)
      Photograph No. 2317
    - Cape Mugford, Labrador (Box 46, Folder 124)
      Photograph No. 2318-2338
    - Cape Ninik, [Labrador?] (Box 46, Folder 125)
      Photograph No. 2339
    - Cape Raven, Newfoundland (Box 46, Folder 126)
      Photograph No. 2340
    - Cape Uivuk, Labrador (Box 46, Folder 127)
      Photograph No. 2341-2342
    - Cape Webeck, [Labrador?] (Box 46, Folder 128)
      Photograph No. 2343
    - Caribou Island, Labrador (Box 46, Folder 129)
      Photograph No. 2344-2346
    - Caster River, Newfoundland (Box 47, Folder 130)
      Photograph No. 2347
    - Clarke's Boulder, [Newfoundland?] (Box 47, Folder 131)
      Photograph No. 2348
    - Coachman's Cove, Newfoundland (Box 47, Folder 132)
      Photograph No. 2349
    - Codroy Valley, Newfoundland (Box 47, Folder 133)
      Photograph No. 2350-2351
    - Conche, Newfoundland (Box 47, Folder 134)
      Photograph No. 2352-2357
    - Cook's Harbor, Newfoundland (Box 47, Folder 135)
      Photograph No. 2358
    - Cremelière, [Quebec?] (Box 47, Folder 136)
      Photograph No. 2359
    - Cut Throat Tickle, Labrador (Box 47, Folder 137)
      Photograph No. 2360
    - Davis Inlet, Labrador (Box 47, Folder 138)
      Photograph No. 2361-2365
    - Deer Island, [Newfoundland?] (Box 47, Folder 139)
      Photograph No. 2366
    - Domino Run, Labrador (Box 47, Folder 140)
      Photograph No. 2367-2379
    - Eagle River, Labrador (Box 47, Folder 141)
      Photograph No. 2380-2400
    - Eclipse, Labrador (Box 47, Folder 142)
      Photograph No. 2401-2403
    - Emily Harbor, [Newfoundland?] (Box 47, Folder 143)
      Photograph No. 2404
    - Exploits River, Newfoundland (Box 47, Folder 144)
      Photograph No. 2405-2406
    - Exploits Run, Newfoundland (Box 47, Folder 145)
      Photograph No. 2407-2408
    - Ferryland, Newfoundland (Box 47, Folder 146)
      Photograph No. 2409
    - Fillberry Tickle, [Labrador?] (Box 47, Folder 147)
      Photograph No. 2410
    - Flatrock, Newfoundland (Box 47, Folder 148)
      Photograph No. 2411
    - Ford's Harbor, [Newfoundland?] (Box 47, Folder 149)
      Photograph No. 2412-2413
    - Fortune Bight, Newfoundland (Box 47, Folder 150)
      Photograph No. 2414-2415
    - Fox Harbor, Labrador (Box 47, Folder 151)
      Photograph No. 2416-2423
    - George's Cove, Labrador (Box 47, Folder 152)
      Photograph No. 2424-2429
    - Grand Galets Bay, Newfoundland (Box 47, Folder 153)
      Photograph No. 2430-2431
    - Grandfather's Cove, [Labrador?] (Box 47, Folder 154)
      Photograph No. 2432
    - Gready Islands, Labrador (Box 47, Folder 155)
      Photograph No. 2433-2437
    - Grenfell River, [Labrador?] (Box 47, Folder 156)
      Photograph No. 2438-2441
    - Griguet, Newfoundland (Box 47, Folder 157)
      Photograph No. 2442-2454
    - Hamilton River, Labrador (Box 47, Folder 158)
      Photograph No. 2455-2472
    - Hatter's Cove, Labrador (Box 47, Folder 159)
      Photograph No. 2473-2474
    - Hawke's Harbor, Labrador (Box 47, Folder 160)
      Photograph No. 2475-2483
    - Humber River, Newfoundland (Box 47, Folder 161)
      Photograph No. 2484-2488
    - Indian Cove, Labrador (Box 47, Folder 162)
      Photograph No. 2489-2496
    - Indian Tickle, Labrador (Box 47, Folder 163)
      Photograph No. 2497-2499
    - Ireland Bight, Newfoundland (Box 47, Folder 164)
      Photograph No. 2500-2512
    - Jackson's Arm, Newfoundland (Box 47, Folder 165)
      Photograph No. 2513-2515
    - Kaumajet Mountains, Labrador (Box 47, Folder 166)
      Photograph No. 2516
    - Kennemish, Labrador (Box 47, Folder 167)
      Photograph No. 2517-2518
    - Kepekok, [Labrador?] (Box 47, Folder 168)
      Photograph No. 2519
    - Kiglapait Mountains, Labrador (Box 47, Folder 169)
      Photograph No. 2520
    - Kikkertaksoak Island, Labrador (Box 47, Folder 170)
      Photograph No. 2521-2522
    - Lewis Bay, [Labrador?] (Box 47, Folder 171)
      Photograph No. 2523-2525
    - Logy Bay, Newfoundland (Box 47, Folder 172)
      Photograph No. 2526-2527
    - Long Island, Newfoundland (Box 47, Folder 173)
      Photograph No. 2528-2534
    - Long Lake, [Newfoundland?] (Box 47, Folder 174)
      Photograph No. 2535
    - Long Tickle, [Labrador?] (Box 47, Folder 175)
      Photograph No. 2536
    - Lumaneek, Labrador (Box 47, Folder 176)
      Photograph No. 2537-2540
    - Majette, [Labrador?] (Box 47, Folder 177)
      Photograph No. 2541-2544
    - Mark's Island, [Labrador?] (Box 47, Folder 178)
      Photograph No. 2545
    - Mugford Tickle, Labrador (Box 47, Folder 179)
      Photograph No. 2546-2561
    - Naksarektok, [Labrador?] (Box 48, Folder 180)
      Photograph No. 2562
    - Nakvak, Labrador (Box 48, Folder 181)
      Photograph No. 2563-2566
    - Nepartok Bay, Labrador (Box 48, Folder 182)
      Photograph No. 2567
    - Nipper's Harbor, Newfoundland (Box 48, Folder 183)
      Photograph No. 2568-2569
    - Norris Arm, Newfoundland (Box 48, Folder 184)
      Photograph No. 2570-2571
    - North Tickle, [Newfoundland?] (Box 48, Folder 185)
      Photograph No. 2572
    - North West Bight, [Labrador?] (Box 48, Folder 186)
      Photograph No. 2573-2576
    - Patty's Cove, Labrador (Box 48, Folder 187)
      Photograph No. 2577-2578
    - Petty Harbor, Newfoundland (Box 48, Folder 188)
      Photograph No. 2579
    - Pistolet Bay, Newfoundland (Box 48, Folder 189)
      Photograph No. 2580-2584
    - Pomiaduk Bay, [Labrador?] (Box 48, Folder 190)
      Photograph No. 2585
    - Port aux Basques, Newfoundland (Box 48, Folder 191)
      Photograph No. 2586-2588
    - Port Manvers, Labrador (Box 48, Folder 192)
      Photograph No. 2589
    - Pouch Cove, Newfoundland (Box 48, Folder 193)
      Photograph No. 2590-2591
    - Puffin Island, Labrador (Box 48, Folder 194)
      Photograph No. 2592
    - Quirpon Harbor, Newfoundland (Box 48, Folder 195)
      Photograph No. 2593-2599
    - Ragged Islands, Labrador (Box 48, Folder 196)
      Photograph No. 2600-2607
    - Rigolet, Labrador (Box 48, Folder 197)
      Photograph No. 2608-2625
    - River of Ponds, Newfoundland (Box 48, Folder 198)
      Photograph No. 2626
    - Rockey Harbor, [Labrador?] (Box 48, Folder 199)
      Photograph No. 2627-2628
    - Rowsell's Harbor, Labrador (Box 48, Folder 200)
      Photograph No. 2629-2632
    - Ryan's Bay, Labrador (Box 48, Folder 201)
      Photograph No. 2633-2634
    - Saglek Bay, Labrador (Box 48, Folder 202)
      Photograph No. 2635-2643
    - St. Augustine Bay, Quebec (Box 48, Folder 203)
      Photograph No. 2644
    - St. Barbe Island, Newfoundland (Box 48, Folder 204)
      Photograph No. 2645
    - St. Golius Harbor, Newfoundland (Box 48, Folder 205)
      Photograph No. 2646-2647
    - St. John Island, Newfoundland (Box 48, Folder 206)
      Photograph No. 2648
    - St. John's Harbor, Newfoundland
      - General views (Box 48, Folder 207)
        Photograph No. 2649-2695
      - Cathedral (Box 48, Folder 208)
        Photograph No. 2696-2699
      - King George V Seamen's Institute (Box 48, Folder 209)
        Photograph No. 2700-2714
      - Lighthouse (Box 48, Folder 210)
        Photograph No. 2715-2717
      - Public buildings and monuments (Box 48, Folder 211)
        Photograph No. 2718-2721
    - St. Karl's Cove, [Newfoundland?] (Box 48, Folder 212)
      Photograph No. 2722-2732
    - St. Mary's Bay, Newfoundland (Box 48, Folder 213)
      Photograph No. 2733-2736
    - Sandwich Bay, Labrador (Box 48, Folder 214)
      Photograph No. 2737
    - Sandy Cove, [Labrador?] (Box 48, Folder 215)
      Photograph No. 2738
    - Seal Island, Labrador (Box 48, Folder 216)
      Photograph No. 2739-2744
    - Seaplane Cove, Labrador (Box 48, Folder 217)
      Photograph No. 2745-2746
    - Servaluk, Labrador (Box 48, Folder 218)
      Photograph No. 2747
    - Smoky Run, Labrador (Box 48, Folder 219)
      Photograph No. 2748-2753
    - Snug Harbor, Labrador (Box 48, Folder 220)
      Photograph No. 2754-2758
    - Sops Run, Newfoundland (Box 48, Folder 221)
      Photograph No. 2759
    - Spotted Islands, Labrador (Box 48, Folder 222)
      Photograph No. 2760-2768
    - Tabors Island, [Labrador?] (Box 48, Folder 223)
      Photograph No. 2769
    - Tessiusak, [Labrador?] (Box 48, Folder 224)
      Photograph No. 2770
    - Thank God Harbor, [Labrador?] (Box 48, Folder 225)
      Photograph No. 2771
    - Tilt Cove, [Newfoundland?] (Box 48, Folder 226)
      Photograph No. 2772
    - Trinity Bay, Newfoundland (Box 48, Folder 227)
      Photograph No. 2773
    - Tub Harbor, Labrador (Box 48, Folder 228)
      Photograph No. 2774
    - Turner's Bight, Labrador (Box 48, Folder 229)
      Photograph No. 2775-2776
    - Twillingate, Newfoundland
      - General views (Box 49, Folder 230)
        Photograph No. 2777-2794
      - Hospital (Box 49, Folder 231)
        Photograph No. 2795-2822
    - Ungava Bay, Labrador (Box 49, Folder 232)
      Photograph No. 2823-2826
    - Venison Tickle, Labrador (Box 49, Folder 233)
      Photograph No. 2827-2832
    - W. St. Modeste, [Newfoundland?] (Box 49, Folder 234)
      Photograph No. 2833
    - West Turnavik, Labrador (Box 49, Folder 235)
      Photograph No. 2834-2841
    - Western Arm, [Labrador?] (Box 49, Folder 236)
      Photograph No. 2842
    - Whale Harbor, [Labrador?] (Box 49, Folder 237)
      Photograph No. 2843
    - White Bear Island, Labrador (Box 49, Folder 238)
      Photograph No. 2844
    - William's Harbor, Newfoundland (Box 49, Folder 239)
      Photograph No. 2845-2846
    - Windsor Harbor, [Labrador?] (Box 49, Folder 240)
      Photograph No. 2847-2849
    - Inidentified buildings (Box 49, Folder 241)
      Photograph No. 2850-2918
    - Unidentified settlements (Box 49, Folder 242-243)
      Photograph No. 2919-3077
    - Unidentified landscapes (Box 49, Folder 244-245)
      Photograph No. 3078-3149, 10,409-10,488
    - Unidentified landscapes (Box 50, Folder 245a-246)
      Photograph No. 3150-3289
  - Labrador Survey
    - "The Forbes-Grenfell North Labrador Expedition, 1931" (Box 50, Folder 247-250)
      Photograph No. 3290-3467
    - "The Forbes-Grenfell North Labrador Expedition, 1931" (Box 51, Folder 251)
      Photograph No. 3468-3526
  - "Liv'eres" (Box 51, Folder 252-254)
    Photograph No. 3527-3723
  - Eskimos
    - Portraits (Box 51, Folder 255-256)
      Photograph No. 3724-3832
    - Daily life (Box 52, Folder 257-258)
      Photograph No. 3833-3952
    - Housing (Box 52, Folder 259)
      Photograph No. 3953-3969
    - Artifacts (Box 52, Folder 260)
      Photograph No. 3970-3974
  - Indians
    - Portraits (Box 52, Folder 261)
      Photograph No. 3975-3994
    - Daily life (Box 52, Folder 262)
      Photograph No. 3995-4000
    - Housing (Box 52, Folder 263)
      Photograph No. 4001-4013
  - Agriculture and Livestock (Box 52, Folder 264)
    Photograph No. 4014-4034
  - Fishing (Box 52, Folder 265)
    Photograph No. 4035-4094
  - Hunting (Box 52, Folder 266-267)
    Photograph No. 4095-4210
  - Transportation
    - Airplanes (Box 53, Folder 268)
      Photograph No. 4211-4247
    - Dog sleds (Box 53, Folder 269-271)
      Photograph No. 4248-4480
    - Motor vehicles and iceboats (Box 53, Folder 272)
      Photograph No. 4481-4485
    - Railroads (Box 53, Folder 273)
      Photograph No. 4486-4491
    - Reindeer (Box 53, Folder 274-275)
      Photograph No. 4492-4612
    - Ships, A-F (Box 53, Folder 276)
      Photograph No. 4613-4662
    - Ships, G-M (Box 54, Folder 277)
      Photograph No. 4663-4720
    - Ships, N-Ste (Box 54, Folder 278)
      Photograph No. 4721-4790
    - Ships, "Strathcona I" (Box 54, Folder 279-280)
      Photograph No. 4791-4903
    - Ships, "Strathcona II" T-W (Box 54, Folder 281)
      Photograph No. 4904-4949
    - Ships, unidentified (Box 54, Folder 282-283)
      Photograph No. 4950-5123
    - Ships, unidentified (Box 55, Folder 284)
      Photograph No. 5124-5182
  - Icebergs (Box 55, Folder 285-287)
    Photograph No. 5183-5383
  - Wilfred T. Grenfell
    - 1873-1918 (Box 55, Folder 288-290)
      Photograph No. 5384-5546
    - 1919-1940, undated (Box 56, Folder 291-295)
      Photograph No. 5547-5816
    - Anglesey Boy's Brigade Holiday Camp, 1890-1892 (Box 56, Folder 296)
      Photograph No. 5817-5879
    - Universities Camp for Public School Boys, Lee-on-Solent, 1898 Jul (Box 56, Folder 297)
      Photograph No. 5880-5910
    - Universities Camp at Fritton for Public School Boys, 1899 (Box 56, Folder 298)
      Photograph No. 5911-5959
    - North Sea Fleet tours, 1891-1892 (Box 56, Folder 299)
      Photograph No. 5960-5984
    - North Sea Fleet tours, 1898 Dec (Box 57, Folder 300)
      Photograph No. 5985-6037
    - North Sea Fleet tours, 1899 Apr-May (Box 57, Folder 301)
      Photograph No. 6038-6066
    - Trip to Labrador, 1892 (Box 57, Folder 302)
      Photograph No. 6067-6118
    - Trip to Labrador, 1899-1900 (Box 57, Folder 303-304)
      Photograph No. 6119-6261
    - Sled trip in Labrador, 1920 Sep-1921 Jun (Box 57, Folder 305)
      Photograph No. 6262-6315
    - Labrador trip,[ca. 1925-1930] (Box 57, Folder 306)
      Photograph No. 6316-6403
    - Labrador cruise, 1931 Jun-Sep (Box 57, Folder 307)
      Photograph No. 6404-6529
  - Wilfred T. Grenfell Family
    - Anne Elizabeth (MacClanahan) Grenfell
      - 1901-1938 (Box 58, Folder 308-309)
        Photograph No. 6530-6596
      - Bryn Mawr, [ca. 1904-1906] (Box 58, Folder 310)
        Photograph No. 6597-6651
      - Huron Mountain Club, [Minnesota?], 1907, 1909 (Box 58, Folder 311)
        Photograph No. 6652-6682
      - European tour, 1909 (Box 58, Folder 312)
        Photograph No. 6683-6690
      - Personal photograph album, [ca. 1908-1909] (Box 58, Folder 313)
        Photograph No. 6691-6729
    - Wilfred T. Grenfell, Jr.
      - 1911 (Box 58, Folder 314)
        Photograph No. 6730-6772
      - With family, 1912-1943 (Box 58, Folder 315)
        Photograph No. 6773-6847
      - Trip to Germany, 1934 summer (Box 58, Folder 316)